Help!
No! Please, no!
Please, no!
♪ It will joy
and comfort give you ♪
♪ Take it then
wherever you go ♪
- ♪ Precious name ♪
- ♪ Oh, how sweet ♪
♪ Hope of Earth
and joy of Heav'n ♪
- ♪ Precious name ♪
- ♪ Oh, how sweet ♪
♪ Hope of Earth
and joy of Heav'n... ♪
That's beautiful. What is it?
Sarah's favorite.
She'd climb up
on the dining room table
and sing that hymn
every time we had guests.
Oh.
Here you are.
Oh, thank you.
Julia.
Right.
Um, are those my keys?
No.
Evelyn.
I keep mace on there.
They're mine.
No.
I wouldn't want you
hurting yourself.
What?
Evelyn, please.
Thank you.
Why do you carry mace?
Um, I live alone, so.
But you live with me now.
It's getting late.
We should get you to bed soon.
I'll just check your
blood pressure first, okay?
Okay.
I want you
to put your hand right here.
Hm.
Is that comfortable?
So, is Sarah your daughter?
You know, we never locked
our doors when we were young.
We had no need to.
That must've been nice.
It was nice.
We'd be out all day, wandering.
Come home in the evening
and our parents never worried.
Maybe they did.
Maybe you just didn't notice.
Maybe.
Okay.
Am I okay?
Yeah. 116 over 75.
You're good.
Hmm.
Just hold on.
Okay.
Good.
There's a storm coming.
Yeah.
I was supposed to fix your room.
Oh, it's fine.
My room was made up.
Thank you.
Are you done?
Yes.
Okay. That smells nice.
Mm-hmm.
Did we uh,
did I show you around?
I have everything I need.
Thank you.
All right. Hmm.
I forget sometimes.
How are you feeling?
Like hell.
Well, I'll be right
in the next room
if you need anything.
Thank you. Uh...
Julia.
Yes, Julia, and I'm so sorry.
No. No apologies.
It's fine.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, Sarah.
Now I lay me down to sleep.
I pray for all the souls I keep.
Shit!
Uh, shit.
Hi, Dad.
No, I'm not ignoring you.
I'm working.
No, Dad,
I told you I probably...
I'm not gonna make it.
I'm not avoiding it.
It's just,
I... I just got this job.
I can't leave a few days in.
I don't know.
I can't believe
you're asking this.
Dad, I don't know.
Ew.
No, never mind.
I said I don't know,
because it's not
that kind of job.
It could be a few days,
a few weeks.
Of course, I miss her.
What kind of question is that?
Yeah, I get it, but...
Well, what does it matter?
No one's seen me there in years.
Uh, Dad, come on.
I don't go anymore.
You know that.
Well, what difference
does it make?
It doesn't change anything.
Mom knew I loved her!
Dad? Dad?
Listen, I need to go,
so I'll call you again tomorrow
and we can talk
about this then, okay?
Yes, I promise.
Okay.
I love you, too.
Okay, bye.
Jesus.
Like, what is not clear about,
I'll call you to...
What are you doing in my house?
Evelyn?
How do you know my name?
I'm your nurse.
I just helped you to bed.
We spoke about Sarah,
your daughter.
How about you
give me that, yeah?
Let's put it back
by the fireplace.
What do you think?
Yeah? Please.
Did you paint that?
Yes.
Very talented.
I'm quite terrible.
You're an artist?
Nothing serious.
Are those yours, too?
Mm-hmm.
I'd love to see
your other paintings.
- You can hold onto that
if it makes you feel better. - Mm-hmm.
Is that okay?
Okay.
Go first.
Right. Yeah, sure.
Okay.
Wow.
I love the... the detail
on this one.
Mm.
You have a real eye for color.
The way they
contrast each other.
I would've never guessed
these go together, but they do.
My mom taught me everything.
She had an eye like you do.
Is this you?
Long time ago.
And that's your family?
Yeah.
Hmm.
Anthropology.
That's the study
of culture, right?
Art and rituals,
and things like that?
Oh, Randall gave me that
for our first anniversary.
He got it at a, uh,
an art supply store
and then he buried it
at our picnic spot.
Is Randall the guy in the photo?
Yeah. He... he painted, too,
but he took this photograph
of me just before our wedding.
That's the biggest smile
I've ever seen.
Yeah.
He must've been very special.
We were happy.
Hey, it's getting late.
How about we get back,
we get you back to bed?
I'll put this back.
I'm sorry.
No, it's fine.
Julia?
Yeah.
You okay?
Watch your step.
Here we are.
There you go.
Oh.
Thank you, Julia.
What happened to your hands?
Oh.
Oh, nothing.
Just old scars.
Hmm.
That is one gorgeous necklace.
Oh, why thank you.
It was my mother's.
Is that gold?
Um, I think so, yeah.
What a lovely piece.
Oh, my.
Do you think
you could help me down?
Of course.
That's it. There we go.
Oh, my.
Ooh, you know,
all my bones creak.
Okay.
Ooh.
Hmm, pray with me.
Pardon?
Pray with me.
I used to think that
prayer was ridiculous, too,
before Sarah, but somehow asking
an all-powerful being
for something seems arrogant.
Hmm.
But there is grace
in supplication.
Hmm?
I don't really pray
to God anymore.
Who said anything about God?
Thank you, dear.
Now clasp your hands.
Now I lay me down to sleep.
Go on.
I pray for all the souls I keep.
If I should die before I wake,
I pray the souls
another body will take.
If I should live
for a few more days,
I pray my keeper
to guide my ways.
In my name,
I pray,
I pray.
Now I lay me down to sleep.
I pray for all
of the souls I keep.
If I should die before I wake,
I pray the souls
another body will take.
If I should live
for a few more days,
I pray my keeper
to guide my way.
Okay.
Yeah.
Uh, yeah, I'll just...
Later.
Not bad.
That's cute.
That's gross.
Color contrast, my ass.
You're one dark lady.
Yeah, you're okay.
Weird.
Evelyn? Are you up again?
Can I help you?
Is Evelyn home?
Sorry, who are you?
Randall.
You're Julia, right?
Your agency put us in touch.
Yeah, yeah.
Of course, hi.
Come in.
You're Evelyn's husband.
Well, not for a long time now.
Oh.
Is she up?
I just put her to bed.
I hope she's awake.
I drove a long way out.
She should be.
She was just praying, so...
Evie, praying?
Yeah.
Did you... did you hit the storm
on the way here?
No, I came
from the other direction.
I hope it doesn't get too bad.
How is she doing?
Uh, it's been
a pretty rough night.
She's been kind of in and out.
She spoke about you, though.
Is something wrong?
No.
Uh, no. It's just,
I haven't seen this one in a long time.
There she is.
Randall?
Hey, Evie.
Huh.
You got old.
Yeah, they say that happens.
You're still as lovely as ever.
And you're still full of shit.
I've missed you.
I know.
Is Earl here with you?
My brother died 12 years ago.
You went to the funeral.
I did?
It's okay.
None of us are
what we used to be, right?
And Marlene?
She left me.
That's been
a long time now, too.
I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
No, I'm not.
How long are you staying?
As long as I need to.
You have help now,
so you don't need to worry
about anything.
You have been thinking
about her.
Every day.
Me too.
So why are you here?
Where did you find
this inscription?
Why didn't you wait
for me to get back?
We could've discussed it,
figured out something together.
Where is it, Evelyn?
I know you have it.
No.
Nobody else knows
where we buried it.
No. No.
- Why would you take it?
- No.
If it's for this,
you know what can happen.
- Where is it?
- Hey.
Go away.
I'm trying to protect you!
- No.
- Hey! Don't touch her.
Leave me, leave me,
leave me alone.
Go away.
You need to leave.
Now.
Make him go. Make him go.
Okay.
Make sure he leaves.
I promise.
I don't wanna see him.
If you don't get out
of this house in 30 seconds,
I'm calling the police.
I don't care who you are.
You have no idea
what's going on here.
Yeah.
It's gonna be okay, all right?
Please, please get rid of him.
I never wanna see him again.
All right, just... just calm down.
I'll be right back.
Where are you hiding it?
Hey! Get out!
Just leave!
Watch yourself.
Evelyn, what are you doing?
It's freezing.
I wanna be out here when I pass.
Let's not talk about
that. You've still got time.
Why would anyone
want a job like this?
Why would you want to
watch someone die?
Because no one
should have to die alone.
We all die alone.
What was that all
about up there?
Oh, we don't agree on
things. We never did, really.
I tried to get him
to understand but he... he blames me.
What happened to Sarah?
Oh, Sarah.
I miss her so much.
Can't hide from our past.
Sometimes we have
to confront it and accept it.
Is everything okay?
I'm going to be sick.
Come on, let's go inside.
Oh, dear. Come here.
Ugh, oh, I'm so sorry.
No, it's okay. It's fine.
Let's get you cleaned up, okay?
I'll find you a blanket.
All right.
Evelyn?
Oh, my... Evelyn?
Evelyn, what are you doing?
Stop that, please.
Evelyn!
Stop.
Eve...
Jesus Christ.
It's not working.
The song will work. It always works.
Brush my hair.
What the fuck is this?
Sure, my love.
It don't feel so good. My tummy hurts.
Do you want me to rub your tummy?
Mom?
What is it?
Why do you have that?
Oh, this?
Are you taping me?
- I...
- Where the fuck am I?
I was... I was worried about
you and wanted to record
any changes.
Changes?
Sorry, I should've
asked you. I'll turn it off.
Is it off?
Yes.
Don't ever do that again!
Shit.
Sarah?
Get out!
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Oh, my God, Evelyn,
what did you do?
What the hell?
What is this?
Hello?
What... What is...
What the fuck?
Is there a back door?
I think I can open it.
Pete!
Go check upstairs.
Sh... shit.
Oh!
Office is clear.
Kitchen's clear.
Evelyn, where are you?
I just want to talk!
Okay.
Hey.
Oh, fuck! Oh!
Calm down.
Where do I go?
Where the fuck do I go?
Shit!
Okay, okay.
Just find something.
There's gotta be something
in here.
Okay. Find scissors.
Okay.
Shit.
Fucking...
Fucking shit!
She blinded me, man.
Yeah, well.
- I'm scared.
- Quiet!
It fucking burns!
Hey, man up!
You grab him.
I can't look
for anyone right now.
Hey, shut up. All right?
Just be quiet.
We just want to talk.
We're running out of time.
Give me a minute.
Go downstairs.
I'm not gonna hurt anybody.
Can we talk?
I'd like to explain.
Stay away!
This is not how
I wanted this to go.
How did you want this to go?
This is a misunderstanding.
Just leave us alone!
You can stay in there
if it makes you feel better.
It does.
Evelyn's in trouble.
Where is she?
I don't know!
And I wouldn't tell you
if I did.
Is she still in the house?
What the fuck did I just say?
Nothing I can tell you will
make you believe me.
Hell, I didn't believe it myself
and I lived through it.
Through what?
We had a child.
She died because
we couldn't protect her.
That's a lie.
We could've protected her,
but we got careless.
We thought we knew better
and it destroyed us.
Evelyn never forgave herself
and...
And what?
She was my first love, you know?
Randall, we got her!
Just leave her alone!
I'm sorry.
This is for your own good.
Let me out!
Randall, Peter, we got her.
Calm down.
Get out of my house!
Take a deep breath. Calm down.
Don't touch me.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Of course, it's you. Stay away.
Peter, give her some space.
Evelyn, put that down.
You shouldn't be touching that.
Please, hand it over, Evie.
Let me take it off your hands.
I just want to put it
someplace safe.
There is no place safe.
It was safe until you started
messing with it.
Why, Evie?
Because I miss her!
I'm sorry about
the way things turned out.
Yeah, you left me
right after she died
when I needed you the most.
What do you want me to say?
That I couldn't face you after?
That the... the guilt
ate me up inside?
I got it wrong and I've had
to live with that.
But I can do it right this time.
I know how. Trust me.
Trust you?
That's what got her killed.
I translated one of the words
that you sent me.
It's an incantation, isn't it?
Tell me!
We can still do the right thing.
That's your weakness, always
wanting to do the right thing,
huh, when there's only pain
and loss and suffering.
This is not going
to bring Sarah back!
Give it to me!
Why?
So you can bury me again?
Who... who am I talking to right now?
What have you done with Evelyn?
I wear her like a coat.
Oh, my God.
Let's get outta here.
Oh, let's call the others.
Get out, quick, quick.
Evelyn? Evelyn?
Oh, my God,
what did they do to you?
They're gone now.
Let's get you changed.
Oh, my goodness.
Here we go.
Where are you hurt?
Oh, look at your hand.
What did they do to you?
Okay, let's... let's sit here.
Yeah, there you go.
- Want to give me that?
- No.
Wash your hands, okay?
Okay. Okay. Here we go.
All right. There you go.
Got this one.
That's great.
Where's your phone?
- In the office.
- Okay.
We'll find it, yeah?
You'll be okay.
Yeah.
Here we are. All right.
Okay, you good?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- All right. Here we are.
All right.
Let's sit right here.
Where is it?
Okay, great.
For fuck's sake!
What do they want?
What... this?
What... what is it?
Is it worth a lot of money?
This is not...
You should be surrounded
by loved ones,
not by someone like me.
Sarah, if you ever get to hear this,
your suffering is because of us.
Too many risks.
Too much contact
with the other side.
We have to bury her.
I'm sorry we put all this ahead of you.
I'll never expose you
to this again.
What's wrong with us?
Okay. Father, start the prayer.
I'm sorry. It was meant for...
Stop, stop. Please don't do this.
I'm sorry.
Is that...
Help me. Mommy!
- Your baby?
- No, mommy, please.
She's not okay.
She will be fine.
Stop! Stop!
She'll look in the box.
What... what is this?
Look at her!
Help!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
There he is.
Get off!
We've got to bury the de...
Let's get you warmed up.
I brought her to evil.
It's my fault.
- It's all my fault.
- Don't say that.
It's true.
All right. You're okay.
Okay.
No, no. I don't want it.
Nice, nice, nice, nice, nice.
You feeling better?
This one's nice.
Things happen, Evelyn.
I'm sure you and Randall
were great parents.
You don't know that.
I know I blamed myself
for my mom's death.
I mean, I know,
I didn't make her sick,
but I... I should've been there
for her, and I... I just... I...
I couldn't do it.
It's easier to take care
of strangers.
Hmm.
Fuck's sake.
Just stay here.
I just want to talk!
Please just don't move!
I called the cops!
You need to get
the fuck outta here now!
Listen to me.
I know it's confusing, but...
but that's not Evelyn in there.
It's something dangerous.
The only dangerous thing here
is you and your psycho friends!
She killed Peter!
He's dead because of her!
She didn't kill anybody!
She's fucking old!
Stay the fuck back!
That little ivory statue
that she has,
you're not safe as long
as that thing is in the house.
The statue is the problem?
It's an anchor, a vessel
for something dark.
It's attached itself to her.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
It'll kill you both!
We can't leave here without...
Okay, fine!
If I get it for you,
will you leave?
Yes.
That's all we want!
Just stay outside.
I'll go get it!
You're doing the right thing.
You think you can
take this from me?
Huh?
For fuck's sake, Evelyn, I
told you to stay over there!
Put the knife down!
No!
Please, let's talk.
Maybe we can work
something out with them.
Evelyn, everything's
gonna be okay.
You're safe.
Why don't you just give me...
No! No!
Evelyn, stop!
You, stop!
Evelyn, stop.
Where are you?
Fuck.
Evelyn?
Hello?
Hurry up!
Come on.
You're here.
We can still salvage this.
Trust me.
Like Peter did?
What is this?
What are we dealing
with, Randall?
Nothing I can't handle.
What happened?
We were too late.
It's already in her.
We lost Peter,
there was nothing we could do.
We need to get it
into the statue
and back in here.
Randall, this is very dangerous.
It's not because
I'm no longer authorized.
It's...
You remember what happened
last time we tried this?
You're all I've got.
I'm not gonna lose both of them.
I understand.
Randall, this one,
this one is strong.
Stronger than anything
we ever faced before and you know it.
- This time is different.
- What's this?
We can destroy it.
We only need one word.
This is an incantation
of the blood of Christ.
Blood of Christ.
Evelyn figured it out.
No more hiding it away.
I can finally make it pay
for everything that it's done.
Send it back to hell
where it belongs.
Hey, if this time
it doesn't work?
We're going through the front.
Stick together, near the back.
Holler if you see her.
Don't do anything
until I'm there.
Go on.
I'm going to fix this.
She's stronger than she looks.
If it goes south, just run out.
Evelyn, is that you?
Honey, do you know why you're here?
Why... why are my hands tied?
- What the hell?
So you don't hurt yourself again.
Remember last night?
No.
You scratched until your face bled.
Stop it.
How do you feel?
My tummy really hurts.
I don't feel good.
Do you remember when we went on the dig?
Do you remember
what school you go to?
No! No!
What do you remember?
No. Mommy!
Sarah?
I pray the soul is another body to take.
I only remember
that you're a shit mother!
Sarah! -
Randall!
Oh, my God.
Is that all you've got, old man?
Hmm?
Stop it!
No!
Look at her!
What have we done?
Shit.
Evelyn, where have you been?
Why do you have that?
You're scaring me.
Please don't hurt me.
Why are you following me?
I was looking for you. Where were you?
Do you remember anything?
I remember some things.
I had a dream about my mother,
not long after she passed.
We were making dinner together,
like every other night.
And right in the middle,
she stopped
and said she had to go.
So I ran after her
to say goodbye,
but she kept walking
like she didn't hear me.
So I followed her,
but she was lost,
disappeared into the fog.
How do you know that?
I never told you that.
Evelyn?
Stop, you're freaking me out.
Jules? Jules.
Mom?
Can you come here, please?
I missed you, mija.
This can't...
The last time I saw you was at the airport.
We were saying goodbye
and the sunlight was shining behind you.
- And it was so beautiful.
- You're not my mom.
Oh, Jules,
remember when you were five
and broke your arm?
- Who fed you every meal?
- No. Stop it. Stop it. Please, stop.
When you were 12 and
missed a month of school
with pneumonia,
who nursed you back to health?
Who cried with you
when your prom date
didn't show up?
- I held you. I comforted you.
- Stop.
I was there for you. - No puedo...
It's so cold here. - Stop it.
Please.
Let me see you again.
I said stop it!
Te quiero, mija.
Okay.
Oh, okay.
Oh, what is this?
What is this?
Evelyn!
Way too late.
Time's over.
Edgar, hold her!
Please, hear us!
Nobody's listening!
Surrender her! Don't listen.
By the power of God,
surrender her.
You don't stand a chance!
Oh, shit. Fuck!
I don't have my keys.
Oh, huh, wait!
Just get your fucking keys
and get outta here.
Oh, God, thrust into Hell
Satan and all evil spirits
who wander through the world
for the ruin of souls.
Amen.
Stupid priest.
Evelyn, stop. Be careful!
Get outta here!
Evelyn, fight it.
I know you can.
In the name of God, the Father,
Jesus Christ the Son,
and by the power
of the Holy Spirit,
you will obey me,
you foul thing.
God cast you into a pit of
hellfire, into that pit you shall return.
Oh, I can already
feel her suffering.
Evelyn is stronger
than you will ever be.
That's not
who I'm talking about.
Your daughter
is in eternal torture, because of you.
You failed her, but I,
I can bring her peace.
Don't listen to it.
Leave the flesh
of God's righteous creature
and return to the darkness
from whence you came!
Ah, your souls or hers!
- Little Sarah's blossoming into a lovely woman.
- Shut your mouth, demon!
Oh, you should be honored
to have made
such a precious sacrifice
for me.
I have them both now,
and Evelyn has given up
her defiance
and replaced it with screams.
It's a sweet symphony!
Evie, fight it.
You're stronger than this thing.
You told me that you
found a way and you did.
But I need your help,
so fight it.
Fight it for her!
Fight it for all of us!
The blood of Christ
seals the cage.
By all that's holy in the power
of the Kingdom of Heaven,
I banish you!
Return to your prison.
Your soul's it is.
Make it stop.
What have you done, Evelyn?
You can't leave.
We need to get you
to a hospital.
Come on, let's get you
to my car.
I can't.
Just try
or you'll bleed to death.
Please, help me save her.
What is wrong with you people?
When this is over, bury it.
What?
When everything is done,
put it in the ground.
It's just like in the basement.
Like, what these?
Yeah.
And then... and then...
and then,
there were these letters.
E-L-I-M.
Elim.
What does it mean?
We need to hurry.
No. No, please, let me go.
You can't go.
My dad needs me.
Don't let Evelyn die alone.
Come with me.
Listen, a Christian
ritual's satanic,
but if Elim seals the cage,
Satanism names our power.
I can kill this thing.
I don't wanna do it.
No, I don't wanna...
It should be a perfect fit.
Where do we... wait.
Where are you...
Where are you going?
Just let me leave.
Please.
No!
Julia? Oh, Julia?
Don't be afraid, darling Julia.
Your mother wasn't.
She wasn’t afraid to die.
She was heartbroken.
And I know her pain.
You don't know my mother.
I know her suffering.
And soon you'll have yours!
Go away!
Okay.
We're doing...
Where did it go?
Where does it fucking fit?
What am I supposed to do?
Oh, no, we won't be
needing that anymore.
Tell me, Julia,
would you trade your soul
for hers?
I'm not cutting
any deals with you!
You've abandoned her
like your mother.
The human body is much more fun
than a little statue.
And this one is very tired.
Let her go!
I intend to.
What do you want?
Right now, you!
Sarah doesn't blame you.
It was never your fault.
We did it. We did it.
I'm free.
I think I need a hospital.
Wait, I don't, I don't feel...
What's happening?
I'm sorry.
It has to be this way.
What are you doing?
The only way is if it dies
inside a living vessel.
I have to do it now
while it's weak.
Or before I forget.
Please.
You have been the answer
to all my prayers.
No!
Please, don't kill me!
Not again!
No!
Please, stop!
Please, don't!
Please, don't kill me!
Help me!
Mommy!
Help! Please, help!
Mommy, please help!
Evelyn, what are you doing?
Help, help!
You cannot bury me again.
Evelyn!
Don't!
♪ Take the name of Jesus
with you ♪
♪ Child of sorrow and of woe ♪
♪ It will joy
and comfort give you ♪
♪ Take it then
wherever you go ♪
- ♪ Precious name ♪
- ♪ Oh, how sweet ♪
♪ Hope of Earth
and joy of Heav'n... ♪